<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>
<channel>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://newsbtc.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://newsbtc.com/</link>
	<description>Bitcoin &#38; cryptocurrency news today, price &#38; technical analysis</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 02:56:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
<image>
	<url>https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/cropped-cropped-cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<link>https://newsbtc.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Price Lacking Momentum Above $17k, BTC Holders Are Safe: Here&#8217;s Why</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-lacking-momentum-17k/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 02:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xbtusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511237</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin price extended its increase and tested the $17,500 resistance. BTC corrected gains, but it remains well supported above the $16,800 support. Bitcoin extended its upward move above $17,100 and $17,300 resistance levels. The price is trading near $17,000 and the 100 hourly simple moving average. There was a break below a key bullish trend line with support near $17,050 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair (data feed from Kraken). The pair must stay above the $16,800 support to start a fresh increase. Bitcoin Price Remains Supported Bitcoin price settled above the $17,000 resistance zone and extended its increase. BTC was able to clear the $17,100 and $17,200 resistance levels. The price even spiked above $17,400 and traded close to the $17,500 resistance zone. However, the bears were active near the $17,500 resistance zone. A high was formed near $17,440 and the price started a downside correction. Bitcoin price declined below the $17,200 level and the 100 hourly simple moving average. There was a break below a key bullish trend line with support near $17,050 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair. The price traded as low as $16,888 and is currently rising. It is trading near $17,000 and the 100 hourly simple moving average. It is trading above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the recent decline from the $17,440 swing high to $16,888 low. On the upside, an immediate resistance is near the $17,165 level. It is near the 50% Fib retracement level of the recent decline from the $17,440 swing high to $16,888 low. The first major resistance is near the $17,250 zone, above which the price may perhaps start another steady increase. Source: BTCUSD on TradingView.com In the stated case, the price could rise towards the $17,500 resistance. The next major resistance is near $17,650, above which the price rise towards the $18,000 zone in the near term. More Losses in BTC? If bitcoin fails to start a fresh increase above the $17,165 resistance, there could be more downsides. An immediate support on the downside is near the $16,850 level. The next major support is near the $16,800 zone. A downside break below the $16,800 support might call for a move towards $16,500. Any more losses might call for a test of the key $16,000 support zone in the near term. Technical indicators: Hourly MACD – The MACD is now losing pace in the bearish zone. Hourly RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for BTC/USD is now just below the 50 level. Major Support Levels – $16,800, followed by $16,500. Major Resistance Levels – $17,165, $17,250 and $18,000.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Bitcoin price extended its increase and tested the $17,500 resistance. BTC corrected gains, but it remains well supported above the $16,800 support.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Bitcoin extended its upward move above $17,100 and $17,300 resistance levels.</li>
<li>The price is trading near $17,000 and the 100 hourly simple moving average.</li>
<li>There was a break below a key bullish trend line with support near $17,050 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair (data feed from Kraken).</li>
<li>The pair must stay above the $16,800 support to start a fresh increase.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bitcoin Price Remains Supported</h2>
<p>Bitcoin price settled above the <a href="https://newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-key-trend-18k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$17,000 resistance zone</a> and extended its increase. BTC was able to clear the $17,100 and $17,200 resistance levels.</p>
<p>The price even spiked above $17,400 and traded close to the $17,500 resistance zone. However, the bears were active near the $17,500 resistance zone. A high was formed near $17,440 and the price started a downside correction.</p>
<p>Bitcoin price declined below the $17,200 level and the <a href="https://newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-correction-16-5k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">100 hourly simple moving average</a>. There was a break below a key bullish trend line with support near $17,050 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair.</p>
<p>The price traded as low as $16,888 and is currently rising. It is trading near $17,000 and the 100 hourly simple moving average. It is trading above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the recent decline from the $17,440 swing high to $16,888 low.</p>
<p>On the upside, an immediate resistance is near the $17,165 level. It is near the 50% Fib retracement level of the recent decline from the $17,440 swing high to $16,888 low. The first major resistance is near the $17,250 zone, above which the price may perhaps start another steady increase.</p>
<p><a href="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-511238" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3.png" alt="Bitcoin Price" width="1834" height="845" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3.png 1834w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3-460x212.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3-860x396.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3-768x354.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3-1536x708.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3-750x346.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-3-1140x525.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1834px) 100vw, 1834px" /></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BTCUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>In the stated case, the price could rise towards the $17,500 resistance. The next major resistance is near $17,650, above which the price rise towards the $18,000 zone in the near term.</p>
<h2>More Losses in BTC?</h2>
<p>If bitcoin fails to start a fresh increase above the $17,165 resistance, there could be more downsides. An immediate support on the downside is near the $16,850 level.</p>
<p>The next major support is near the $16,800 zone. A downside break below the $16,800 support might call for a move towards $16,500. Any more losses might call for a test of the key $16,000 support zone in the near term.</p>
<p>Technical indicators:</p>
<p>Hourly MACD – The MACD is now losing pace in the bearish zone.</p>
<p>Hourly RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for BTC/USD is now just below the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Levels – $16,800, followed by $16,500.</p>
<p>Major Resistance Levels – $17,165, $17,250 and $18,000.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/shutterstock_587323760-460x343.jpg" width="460" height="343" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Now Undervalued For 170 Days, How Does This Compare With Previous Bears?</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-undervalued-170-days-compare-previous-bears/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hououin Kyouma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin bear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin bear market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin MVRV Ratio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Realized Cap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Undervalued]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511160</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[On-chain data shows Bitcoin has been undervalued for 170 days now, here&#8217;s how this figure compares with that during the previous bear markets. Bitcoin MVRV Ratio Has Been Stuck Under &#8216;1&#8217; Since 170 Days Ago As pointed out by an analyst in a CryptoQuant post, the lowest point that the MVRV ratio has gone in this bear so far is 0.74. The &#8220;MVRV ratio&#8221; is an indicator that measures the ratio between Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap and its realized cap. Here, the &#8220;realized cap&#8221; is a BTC capitalization model where each circulating coin&#8217;s value is taken as the price at which it was last moved/sold. All these values are then summed up for the entire supply to get the worth of BTC. This is unlike the normal market cap, where all the coins are given the same value as the current Bitcoin price. The usefulness of the realized cap is that it acts as a sort of &#8220;real value&#8221; for the crypto as it takes into account the cost-basis of each holder in the market. Thus, a comparison between the two caps (which is what the MVRV ratio is) can tell us whether the current BTC price is undervalued or overvalued right now. The below chart shows the trend in the Bitcoin MVRV ratio over the last several years: The value of the metric seems to have been below one in recent days &#124; Source: CryptoQuant As you can see in the above graph, the Bitcoin MVRV ratio has been under a value of 1 during the last few months, which means the market cap has been below the realized cap. Historically, the region below 1 is where bear bottoms in the price of the crypto have been observed. On the other hand, the ratio being greater than 3.7 is when tops have been seen. Related Reading: Russian Miners Buy More Bitcoin Mining Rigs In Q4: Report In the 2014-15 bear market, the indicator assumed values lower than 1 for 300 days, and went down to as low as 0.6 during this streak. The 2018-19 bear saw a shorter cycle, however, as it was in this zone for only 134 days. Its lowest point, 0.69, was also not as deep as in 2014-15. In the current Bitcoin cycle, the metric has spent 170 days in this region so far, registering a low of 0.74. The MVRV ratio has therefore now been longer in this region than during the last cycle, but it&#8217;s still not near the length seen in 2014-15. Related Reading: Bitcoin Bearish Signal: MPI Records Highest Value Since April 2022 The metric&#8217;s depth is also not as much as in either of the cycle, so it&#8217;s possible the bear will go deeper still, before Bitcoin finds the bottom of this cycle. BTC Price At the time of writing, Bitcoin&#8217;s price floats around $17.2k, up 7% in the last week. BTC has surged up &#124; Source: BTCUSD on TradingView Featured image from Maxim Hopman on Unsplash.com, charts from TradingView.com, CryptoQuant.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On-chain data shows Bitcoin has been undervalued for 170 days now, here&#8217;s how this figure compares with that during the previous bear markets.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin MVRV Ratio Has Been Stuck Under &#8216;1&#8217; Since 170 Days Ago</h2>
<p>As pointed out by an analyst in a CryptoQuant <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/quicktake/638c053ba60e9b7fa21db775-BTC-MVRV-stays-under-10-more-than-170days">post</a>, the lowest point that the MVRV ratio has gone in this bear so far is 0.74.</p>
<p>The &#8220;<a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-mvrv-ratio-below-average-holder-slips-loss/">MVRV ratio</a>&#8221; is an indicator that measures the ratio between Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap and its realized cap.</p>
<p>Here, the &#8220;<a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-long-term-holders-own-80-realized-cap/">realized cap</a>&#8221; is a BTC capitalization model where each circulating coin&#8217;s value is taken as the price at which it was last moved/sold. All these values are then summed up for the entire supply to get the worth of BTC.</p>
<p>This is unlike the normal market cap, where all the coins are given the same value as the current Bitcoin price. The usefulness of the realized cap is that it acts as a sort of &#8220;real value&#8221; for the crypto as it takes into account the cost-basis of each holder in the market.</p>
<p>Thus, a comparison between the two caps (which is what the MVRV ratio is) can tell us whether the current BTC price is undervalued or overvalued right now.</p>
<p>The below chart shows the trend in the Bitcoin MVRV ratio over the last several years:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://img.cryptoquant.com/53005/quicktake/ipeJHG_4576bbd72a01d796df65af00adec2abac1d0bc77cf0c78aa70782f2412425d07.png" alt="Bitcoin MVRV Ratio" width="1280" height="562" /></p>
The value of the metric seems to have been below one in recent days | Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/quicktake/638c053ba60e9b7fa21db775-BTC-MVRV-stays-under-10-more-than-170days">CryptoQuant</a>
<p>As you can see in the above graph, the Bitcoin MVRV ratio has been under a value of 1 during the last few months, which means the market cap has been below the realized cap.</p>
<p>Historically, the region below 1 is where bear bottoms in the price of the crypto have been observed. On the other hand, the ratio being greater than 3.7 is when tops have been seen.</p>
<p>In the 2014-15 bear market, the indicator assumed values lower than 1 for 300 days, and went down to as low as 0.6 during this streak.</p>
<p>The 2018-19 bear saw a shorter cycle, however, as it was in this zone for only 134 days. Its lowest point, 0.69, was also not as deep as in 2014-15.</p>
<p>In the current Bitcoin cycle, the metric has spent 170 days in this region so far, registering a low of 0.74.</p>
<p>The MVRV ratio has therefore now been longer in this region than during the last cycle, but it&#8217;s still not near the length seen in 2014-15.</p>
<p>The metric&#8217;s depth is also not as much as in either of the cycle, so it&#8217;s possible the bear will go deeper still, before Bitcoin finds the bottom of this cycle.</p>
<h2>BTC Price</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, <a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin-price-up-5-in-last-7-days/">Bitcoin&#8217;s price</a> floats around $17.2k, up 7% in the last week.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-511170 aligncenter" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-3-460x252.png" alt="Bitcoin Price Chart" width="460" height="252" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-3-460x252.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-3-860x471.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-3-768x421.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-3-750x411.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-3.png 975w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" /></p>
BTC has surged up | Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/">BTCUSD on TradingView</a>
Featured image from Maxim Hopman on Unsplash.com, charts from TradingView.com, CryptoQuant.com
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/maxim-hopman-fiXLQXAhCfk-unsplash-460x307.jpg" width="460" height="307" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Crypto Exchange Terminates Half Of Its Employees Amid Bear Market</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/this-crypto-exchange-terminates-half-of-its-employees-amid-bear-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 22:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changpeng zhao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511227</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[The crypto world has had its fair share of drama as the bear market bites down on the entire landscape. In addition, global inflation has also caused most companies to resize their organizational structure. Crypto businesses are now planning for effective cost-management strategies to prevent a collapse. However, the fear in the market for most crypto users is high since trusted firms have collapsed. Related Reading: Metaverse Token Axie Infinity (AXS) Suddenly Pumps 25% – What’s Happening? In light of recent events, Australian cryptocurrency exchange Swyftx has shown 90 of its employees the exit door. It represents a layoff of around 40% of the entire workforce – a significant number. Swyftx CEO Alex Harper said the company is well-positioned to handle the blowout of the FTX storm on the crypto world. He believes the crypto market will continue to decline in 2023. This is the reason behind the massive decrease in the workforce. Layoffs Are Common In Crypto Exchanges Top cryptocurrency exchanges are sizing down their teams to cut costs and prevent wearing out. Other factors have prolonged the current bear market, and this seems to be the only route to stay afloat. Coinbase &#8211; US-based crypto giant laid off around 18% of its staff. Huobi followed suit &#8211; downsizing its staff by 30%. Popular exchange Gemini laid off 10% of its workforce in June, then recruited over 60 new people in July. Other exchanges that include CryptCorn, BitMEX, and Bybit &#8211; reduced their numerical strength. Binance, on the other hand, was one of the few exchanges that expanded operations during the current bearish phase. Who&#8217;s Next? Alex Harper, the Swyftx CEO, broke the news of the layoffs in a letter addressed to employees. He referred to the staff as &#8220;90 talented friends and employees&#8221;. He also distanced Swyftx from any association with the bankrupt exchange FTX. However, he also noted that Swyftx is not immune to the effects of such an event on the crypto market. Harper believes that sizing down a percentage of the workforce will help the organization survive the chilly crypto winter that has claimed many victims. Related Reading: Why Chiliz Is Losing Heat Despite World Cup Pomp; CHZ Down Over 30% According to Harper, Swyftx is one of the top crypto trading organizations; in Australia. He also stated that they are well-positioned to weather the ongoing storm in the crypto market. All affected employees were promised severance pay within seven days to cushion the effects. Also, they will have access to an employee stock ownership plan (ESOP) for the tenure with additional six months. The exchange will also provide them with job search support and employee assistance program (EAP) services. Unfortunately, the FTX crash continues with its devasting fallout, with some crypto exchanges filing for bankruptcy. Featured Image From Pixabay, Charts From Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The crypto world has had its fair share of drama as the bear market bites down on the entire landscape. In addition, global inflation has also caused most companies to resize their organizational structure.</p>
<p>Crypto businesses are now planning for effective cost-management strategies to prevent a collapse. However, the fear in the market for most crypto users is high since trusted firms have collapsed.</p>
<p>In light of recent events, Australian cryptocurrency exchange Swyftx has shown 90 of its employees the exit door. It represents a layoff of around 40% of the entire workforce – a significant number.</p>
<p>Swyftx CEO Alex Harper said the company is well-positioned to handle the blowout of the FTX storm on the crypto world.</p>
<p>He believes the crypto market will continue to decline in 2023. This is the reason behind the massive decrease in the workforce.</p>
<h2>Layoffs Are Common In Crypto Exchanges</h2>
<p>Top cryptocurrency exchanges are sizing down their teams to cut costs and prevent wearing out. Other factors have prolonged the current bear market, and this seems to be the only route to stay afloat.</p>
<p>Coinbase &#8211; US-based crypto giant laid off around 18% of its staff. Huobi followed suit &#8211; downsizing its staff by 30%. Popular exchange Gemini laid off 10% of its workforce in June, then recruited over 60 new people in July.</p>
<p>Other exchanges that include CryptCorn, BitMEX, and Bybit &#8211; reduced their numerical strength. Binance, on the other hand, was one of the few exchanges that expanded operations during the current bearish phase.</p>
Who&#8217;s Next?
<p>Alex Harper, the Swyftx CEO, <a href="https://swyftx.com/au/media/press-releases/swyftx-announces-further-team-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broke the news</a> of the layoffs in a letter addressed to employees. He referred to the staff as &#8220;90 talented friends and employees&#8221;.</p>
<p>He also distanced Swyftx from any association with the bankrupt exchange FTX. However, he also noted that Swyftx is not immune to the effects of such an event on the crypto market.</p>
<p>Harper believes that sizing down a percentage of the workforce will help the organization survive the chilly crypto winter that has claimed many victims.</p>
<p>According to Harper, Swyftx is one of the top crypto trading organizations; in Australia. He also stated that they are well-positioned to weather the ongoing storm in the crypto market.</p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511228 size-large" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18-860x485.png" alt="This Crypto Exchange Terminates Half Of Its Employees Amid Crypto Winter" width="860" height="485" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18-860x485.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18-460x259.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18-768x433.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18-750x423.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18-1140x642.png 1140w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/TOTAL_2022-12-06_02-47-18.png 1519w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511228" class="wp-caption-text">Crypto market trades sideways on the chart | Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/?symbol=CRYPTOCAP%3ATOTAL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crypto Total Market Cap on TradingView.com</a></figcaption>
<p>All affected employees were promised severance pay within seven days to cushion the effects. Also, they will have access to an employee stock ownership plan (ESOP) for the tenure with additional six months.</p>
<p>The exchange will also provide them with job search support and employee assistance program (EAP) services. Unfortunately, the FTX crash continues with its devasting fallout, with some crypto exchanges filing for bankruptcy.</p>
Featured Image From Pixabay, Charts From Tradingview.com
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/airport-g560fad252_1280-460x316.jpg" width="460" height="316" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>For First Time Ever, Bitcoin Hash Ribbon Golden Cross Has Failed</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/first-bitcoin-hash-ribbon-golden-cross-failed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hououin Kyouma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 21:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin golden cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Hash Ribbon Golden Cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin hash ribbons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin hashrate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511126</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[On-chain data shows the Bitcoin Hash Ribbon golden cross has failed to provide an uplift to the price for the first time ever. Bitcoin Hash Ribbons Have Recently Formed A Death Cross As pointed out by an analyst in a CryptoQuant post, the BTC Hash Ribbon model has failed for the first time in the crypto&#8217;s history. The relevant indicator here is the &#8220;mining hashrate,&#8221; which measures the total amount of computing power connected to the Bitcoin network right now. When the value of this metric trends up, it means miners are bringing more mining rigs online currently. On the other hand, a decline suggests these chain validators are ditching the network and disconnecting their machines. The Hash Ribbon is a BTC model that&#8217;s based on two moving averages of the hashrate metric. A &#8220;moving average&#8221; (MA) is the mean value of any quantity that, as its name implies, keeps moving with the metric and changes its value accordingly. Related Reading: Bitcoin Bearish Signal: MPI Records Highest Value Since April 2022 The benefit of an MA is that it smooths out the curve and removes any temporary fluctuations that have no bearing on the long-term trend. In the context of the Hash Ribbon model, the Bitcoin hashrate MAs of interest are the 30-day and the 60-day versions. Here is a chart that shows the trend in these two ribbons over the last few years: Looks like the two MAs of the metric have gone through a cross recently &#124; Source: CryptoQuant As you can see in the above graph, the Bitcoin 60-day MA hashrate has crossed above the 30-day version recently. When this kind of crossover happens, it means the hashrate has been sharply falling recently as the 30-day average has fallen below the longer, 60-day one. Related Reading: This Historic Bitcoin On-Chain Support Level Is Still Not Lost Historically, crosses like these have been bearish death crosses for the price since they are a signal of miner capitulation. Crosses of the opposite kind, on the contrary, have always had a bullish effect on the price of the coin as they indicate that miners are optimistic on the outcome of BTC since they are expanding their operations. The latest golden cross, however, took place a few months ago, but instead of a price rise, a decrease has followed it. Since the death cross is now already in, it would appear that for the first time in Bitcoin&#8217;s history, this bullish crossover has failed to bear any fruits. BTC Price At the time of writing, Bitcoin&#8217;s price floats around $17.3k, up 7% in the last week. BTC seems to have shot up &#124; Source: BTCUSD on TradingView Featured image from mana5280 on Unsplash.com, charts from TradingView.com, CryptoQuant.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On-chain data shows the Bitcoin Hash Ribbon golden cross has failed to provide an uplift to the price for the first time ever.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Hash Ribbons Have Recently Formed A Death Cross</h2>
<p>As pointed out by an analyst in a CryptoQuant <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/quicktake/638c1a25edf9756d0ec3a86c-BTC-Hash-Ribbon-model-fail-for-the-first-time">post</a>, the BTC Hash Ribbon model has failed for the first time in the crypto&#8217;s history.</p>
<p>The relevant indicator here is the &#8220;<a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-hashrate-plummets-following-crypto-winter-what-will-follow-onwards/">mining hashrate</a>,&#8221; which measures the total amount of computing power connected to the Bitcoin network right now.</p>
<p>When the value of this metric trends up, it means miners are bringing more mining rigs online currently. On the other hand, a decline suggests these chain validators are ditching the network and disconnecting their machines.</p>
<p>The Hash Ribbon is a BTC model that&#8217;s based on two moving averages of the hashrate metric. A &#8220;<a href="https://newsbtc.com/sponsored/how-beginners-can-leverage-moving-average-to-profit-from-cryptocurrency/">moving average</a>&#8221; (MA) is the mean value of any quantity that, as its name implies, keeps moving with the metric and changes its value accordingly.</p>
<p>The benefit of an MA is that it smooths out the curve and removes any temporary fluctuations that have no bearing on the long-term trend.</p>
<p>In the context of the Hash Ribbon model, the Bitcoin hashrate MAs of interest are the 30-day and the 60-day versions. Here is a chart that shows the trend in these two ribbons over the last few years:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://img.cryptoquant.com/53005/quicktake/Ttp4bkQ_09839446ef87e62de884ad94c885dc027cf99830f4ba198ab8da418840b9bfe8.png" alt="Bitcoin Hash Ribbon Golden Cross" width="1280" height="553" /></p>
Looks like the two MAs of the metric have gone through a cross recently | Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/quicktake/638c1a25edf9756d0ec3a86c-BTC-Hash-Ribbon-model-fail-for-the-first-time">CryptoQuant</a>
<p>As you can see in the above graph, the Bitcoin 60-day MA hashrate has crossed above the 30-day version recently.</p>
<p>When this kind of crossover happens, it means the hashrate has been sharply falling recently as the 30-day average has fallen below the longer, 60-day one.</p>
<p>Historically, crosses like these have been bearish death crosses for the price since they are a signal of miner capitulation.</p>
<p>Crosses of the opposite kind, on the contrary, have always had a bullish effect on the price of the coin as they indicate that miners are optimistic on the outcome of BTC since they are expanding their operations.</p>
<p>The latest golden cross, however, took place a few months ago, but instead of a price rise, a decrease has followed it. Since the death cross is now already in, it would appear that for the first time in Bitcoin&#8217;s history, this bullish crossover has failed to bear any fruits.</p>
<h2>BTC Price</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, <a href="https://newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-key-trend-18k/">Bitcoin&#8217;s price</a> floats around $17.3k, up 7% in the last week.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-511139 aligncenter" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-2-460x251.png" alt="Bitcoin Price Chart" width="460" height="251" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-2-460x251.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-2-860x470.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-2-768x420.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-2-750x410.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/chart-2.png 975w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" /></p>
BTC seems to have shot up | Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/">BTCUSD on TradingView</a>
Featured image from mana5280 on Unsplash.com, charts from TradingView.com, CryptoQuant.com
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mana5280-rGPDLlMNFF4-unsplash-460x341.jpg" width="460" height="341" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buyers Rule Over Algorand&#8217;s (ALGO) Price Action, Enough To Break Above $0.26?</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/buyers-rule-over-algorands-algo-price-action-enough-to-break-above-0-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[anushsamal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algorand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALGOUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALGOUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511179</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[The Algorand price has been positive over the last 24 hours. Despite minor gains, the altcoin has been moving north. There have been many updates in Algorand&#8217;s ecosystem, which might have brought in a slight appreciation in price. As bulls slowly return to the market, investor interest has also shot up accordingly. The technical outlook of ALGO has depicted that the buyers were dominating the market at the time of writing. Recently, Algorand&#8217;s developments have made it compatible with Cardano, which has created more liquidity injection into the ecosystem. This development could encourage venture capitalists to inject more liquidity into Algorand, thereby reflecting positively on its price. Algorand price depicts positive predictions, but it must be remembered that ALGO&#8217;s ecosystem is developing. ALGO&#8217;s price appreciation is a matter of time as more applications get developed on the platform. For ALGO to topple above the $0.26 resistance mark, buyers have to garner further strength. Related Reading: Metaverse Token Axie Infinity (AXS) Suddenly Pumps 25% – What’s Happening? Algorand Price Analysis: One-Day Chart ALGO was auctioning for $0.24 on the one-day chart after it noted a 1.9% appreciation. At the current moment, it can be said that Algorand is consolidating below its immediate resistance of $0.26. A move above the aforementioned price level will ensure that the altcoin can rally to $0.31. Algorand will lose its current support level unless buying strength increases significantly. In such a case, the nearest support floor for the altcoin was $0.22. The amount of Algorand traded in the last session noted a substantial increase, which indicated that buying strength was shooting up. Technical Analysis Buyers&#8217; interest has returned to the market as the altcoin has started to climb on its chart. The Relative Strength Index spent most of the month in the selling zone, but there had been a recovery on the indicator at press time. For ALGO to touch $0.26, the RSI has to travel above the 50-mark. Similarly, although the Algorand price was progressing upward, it was still below the 20-Simple Moving Average line. With slight accumulation, Algorand would topple above the 20-SMA line. Sellers are currently driving the price momentum. Institutional interest has noted a positive change over the past few trading sessions. There was a downtick in the Chaikin Money Flow, which depicts the capital inflows and outflows. Despite the downtick, CMF was still positive. If capital inflows are to remain above the half-line, demand for ALGO cannot waver. Moving Average Convergence Divergence indicates price momentum and trend change. MACD formed green signal bars after noting a bullish crossover, which meant buyers could act on it and possibly make gains. Related Reading: Why Chiliz Is Losing Heat Despite World Cup Pomp; CHZ Down Over 30% Featured image from VOI, Chart: TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Algorand price has been positive over the last 24 hours. Despite minor gains, the altcoin has been moving north. There have been many updates in Algorand&#8217;s ecosystem, which might have brought in a slight appreciation in price. As bulls slowly return to the market, investor interest has also shot up accordingly.</p>
<p>The technical outlook of ALGO has depicted that the buyers were dominating the market at the time of writing. Recently, Algorand&#8217;s developments have made it compatible with Cardano, which has created more liquidity injection into the ecosystem. This development could encourage venture capitalists to inject more liquidity into Algorand, thereby reflecting positively on its price.</p>
<p>Algorand price depicts positive predictions, but it must be remembered that ALGO&#8217;s ecosystem is developing. ALGO&#8217;s price appreciation is a matter of time as more applications get developed on the platform. For ALGO to topple above the $0.26 resistance mark, buyers have to garner further strength.</p>
<h2>Algorand Price Analysis: One-Day Chart</h2>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511184 size-full" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03.png" alt="Algorand Price" width="1816" height="782" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03.png 1816w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03-460x198.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03-860x370.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03-768x331.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03-1536x661.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03-750x323.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-03-1140x491.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1816px) 100vw, 1816px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511184" class="wp-caption-text">Algorand was priced at $0.24 on the one-day chart | Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ALGOUSD/?exchange=COINBASE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ALGOUSD on TradingView</a></figcaption>
<p>ALGO was auctioning for $0.24 on the one-day chart after it noted a 1.9% appreciation. At the current moment, it can be said that Algorand is consolidating below its immediate resistance of $0.26. A move above the aforementioned price level will ensure that the altcoin can rally to $0.31.</p>
<p>Algorand will lose its current support level unless buying strength increases significantly. In such a case, the nearest support floor for the altcoin was $0.22. The amount of Algorand traded in the last session noted a substantial increase, which indicated that buying strength was shooting up.</p>
<h2 class="text__text__1FZLe text__dark-grey__3Ml43 text__regular__2N1Xr text__large__nEccO body__full_width__ekUdw body__large_body__FV5_X article-body__element__2p5pI" data-testid="paragraph-1">Technical Analysis</h2>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511186 size-full" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46.png" alt="Algorand Price" width="1816" height="695" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46.png 1816w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46-460x176.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46-860x329.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46-768x294.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46-1536x588.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46-750x287.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-39-46-1140x436.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1816px) 100vw, 1816px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511186" class="wp-caption-text">Algorand noted an uptick in buying strength on the one-day chart | Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ALGOUSD/?exchange=COINBASE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ALGOUSD on TradingView</a></figcaption>
<p>Buyers&#8217; interest has returned to the market as the altcoin has started to climb on its chart. The Relative Strength Index spent most of the month in the selling zone, but there had been a recovery on the indicator at press time. For ALGO to touch $0.26, the RSI has to travel above the 50-mark.</p>
<p>Similarly, although the Algorand price was progressing upward, it was still below the 20-Simple Moving Average line. With slight accumulation, Algorand would topple above the 20-SMA line. Sellers are currently driving the price momentum.</p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511187 size-full" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05.png" alt="Algorand Price" width="1816" height="695" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05.png 1816w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05-460x176.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05-860x329.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05-768x294.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05-1536x588.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05-750x287.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/ALGOUSD_2022-12-05_18-40-05-1140x436.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1816px) 100vw, 1816px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511187" class="wp-caption-text">Algorand registered buy signals on the one-day chart | Source:<a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ALGOUSD/?exchange=COINBASE" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> ALGOUSD on TradingView</a></figcaption>
<p>Institutional interest has noted a positive change over the past few trading sessions. There was a downtick in the Chaikin Money Flow, which depicts the capital inflows and outflows. Despite the downtick, CMF was still positive.</p>
<p>If capital inflows are to remain above the half-line, demand for ALGO cannot waver. Moving Average Convergence Divergence indicates price momentum and trend change. MACD formed green signal bars after noting a bullish crossover, which meant buyers could act on it and possibly make gains.</p>
Featured image from VOI, Chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ALGOUSD/?exchange=COINBASE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView.com</a>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/202109101409-main-460x259.jpg" width="460" height="259" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Kicks Off Week Above $17,000, Market Sentiment Turns Optimistic</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-kicks-off-week-above-17000-market-sentiment-turns-optimistic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Reynaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 15:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511192</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin is seeing some green during this week&#8217;s market opening and seems poised to reclaim higher levels in the short term. The number one crypto by market cap experienced some of its worst months in history, but the bulls were able to hold the line at around $15,500.  Related Reading: Why Chiliz Is Losing Heat Despite World Cup Pomp; CHZ Down Over 30% Now, the macroeconomic outlook is changing and could start supporting further profits for risk-on assets. As of this writing, Bitcoin trades at $17,200 with 2% and 5% profits in the last 24 hours and seven days, respectively.  Bitcoin Market Is Getting Back To Normal Data from crypto derivatives exchange Deribit indicates a shift in market sentiment. Participants are more optimistic about Bitcoin after the collapse of the crypto exchange FTX and the fall from the grace of its co-founder and former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried.  This event pushed Bitcoin to a new yearly low and back to its 2020 levels. As seen in the chart below, the BTC Open Interest Weighted Annualized Basis shows that the prices of options contracts were in backwardation.  In other words, options were cheaper than their underlying asset, Bitcoin, following the FTX collapse. The last time BTC saw similar backwardation was in July 2021, during the second capitulation event that triggered a 40% crash in the crypto market.  However, the chart shows that in July 2021, market sentiment and backwardation were far from their November 2022 levels. In addition, the chart shows that the heavy selling triggered by recent events is decreasing, and the crypto market is normalizing. Deribit stated: In July 21, the whole curve didn&#8217;t invert as the longer-dated contracts still traded at a premium. Since 8 November this year, we however see the whole curve trading below spot. BTC&#8217;s Price Short-Term Rally Is More Likely Paired with the above, Deribit claims the BTC 25 put skew, a metric used to gauge market sentiment by looking at the demand for put (sell) options contracts, and their implied volatility is also on the decline. Puts were expensive during the FTX fallout but are returning to their &#8220;normal&#8221; levels. Deribit said: A drop in 1 Month Skew indicates the shorter-dated out the money calls are getting more expensive relative to the out the money puts. In other words, market participants are buying more calls (buy) contracts. These options have a short-term expiration date. Thus, people might be gearing up for a Christmas or end-of-the-year rally.  Related Reading: Metaverse Token Axie Infinity (AXS) Suddenly Pumps 25% – What’s Happening? As NewsBTC reported, the max pain point, the strike price at which a large portion of the contract will expire worthless, stands at $20,000. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bitcoin is seeing some green during this week&#8217;s market opening and seems poised to reclaim higher levels in the short term. The number one crypto by market cap experienced some of its worst months in history, but the bulls were able to hold the line at around $15,500. </strong></p>
<p>Now, the macroeconomic outlook is changing and could start supporting further profits for risk-on assets. As of this writing, Bitcoin trades at $17,200 with 2% and 5% profits in the last 24 hours and seven days, respectively. </p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511197 size-large" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-860x376.png" alt="Bitcoin BTC BTCUSDT" width="860" height="376" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-860x376.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-460x201.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-768x336.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-1536x672.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-750x328.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3-1140x499.png 1140w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-3.png 1813w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511197" class="wp-caption-text">BTC&#8217;s price moving sideways on the 4-hour chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/UJ6TlxFV/?symbol=BINANCE%3ABTCUSDT" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>BTCUSDT Tradingview</strong></a></figcaption>
<h2>Bitcoin Market Is Getting Back To Normal</h2>
<p>Data from crypto derivatives exchange Deribit <a href="https://twitter.com/DeribitExchange/status/1599772576019935232" target="_blank" rel="noopener">indicates</a> a shift in market sentiment. Participants are more optimistic about Bitcoin after the collapse of the crypto exchange FTX and the fall from the grace of its co-founder and former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. </p>
<p>This event pushed Bitcoin to a new yearly low and back to its 2020 levels. As seen in the chart below, the BTC Open Interest Weighted Annualized Basis shows that the prices of options contracts were in backwardation. </p>
<p>In other words, options were cheaper than their underlying asset, Bitcoin, following the FTX collapse. The last time BTC saw similar backwardation was in July 2021, during the second capitulation event that triggered a 40% crash in the crypto market. </p>
<p>However, the chart shows that in July 2021, market sentiment and backwardation were far from their November 2022 levels. In addition, the chart shows that the heavy selling triggered by recent events is decreasing, and the crypto market is normalizing. Deribit stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>In July 21, the whole curve didn&#8217;t invert as the longer-dated contracts still traded at a premium. Since 8 November this year, we however see the whole curve trading below spot.</p></blockquote>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511196 size-large" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2-860x325.jpeg" alt="Bitcoin BTC BTCUSDT Chart 2" width="860" height="325" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2-860x325.jpeg 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2-460x174.jpeg 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2-768x290.jpeg 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2-750x284.jpeg 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2-1140x431.jpeg 1140w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-2.jpeg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511196" class="wp-caption-text">Source: Deribit</figcaption>
BTC&#8217;s Price Short-Term Rally Is More Likely
<p>Paired with the above, Deribit claims the BTC 25 put skew, a metric used to gauge market sentiment by looking at the demand for put (sell) options contracts, and their implied volatility is also on the decline. Puts were expensive during the FTX fallout but are returning to their &#8220;normal&#8221; levels. Deribit said:</p>
<blockquote><p>A drop in 1 Month Skew indicates the shorter-dated out the money calls are getting more expensive relative to the out the money puts.</p></blockquote>
<p>In other words, market participants are buying more calls (buy) contracts. These options have a short-term expiration date. Thus, people might be gearing up for a Christmas or end-of-the-year rally. </p>
<p>As NewsBTC reported, the max pain point, the strike price at which a large portion of the contract will expire worthless, stands at $20,000. </p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-510007 size-large" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-3-860x496.jpg" alt="Bitcoin BTC BTCUSDT Chart 3" width="860" height="496" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-3-860x496.jpg 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-3-460x265.jpg 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-3-768x443.jpg 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-3-750x432.jpg 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Bitcoin-BTC-BTCUSDT-Chart-3.jpg 944w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-510007" class="wp-caption-text">BTC Options&#8217; Open Interest for the December 30th expiry. Source: Deribit</figcaption>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kanchanara-ZmT5ZmEBI3o-unsplash-460x306.jpg" width="460" height="306" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Chiliz Is Losing Heat Despite World Cup Pomp; CHZ Down Over 30%</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/chiliz-is-losing-heat-despite-world-cup-pomp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chiliZ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CHZ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FIFA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Cup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511161</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[Since the beginning of the 2022 2FIFA World Cup, the value of Chiliz native token has plummeted. Due to the discovery of various issues, the sporting event has been met with some controversies. Not to mention that just a week before the World Cup’s start, the collapse of the infamous FTX exchange shook the crypto world. But then, this is not the main point here. Despite some promising advances off-chain, Chiliz continues to struggle. The token is down more than 30% in the last two weeks. There is a lot of bearish evidence in the technicals and stats. If the price drops below $0.1451, short selling becomes an option. This added strain to the already overburdened Chiliz ecosystem, which has had trouble drawing in investors and sports fans despite the testnet release of its Chiliz 2.0 update. However, CoinGecko reported a 1.3% price increase just lately. Related Reading: Litecoin Continues To Surge As Hash Rate Records New ATH – How About LTC Price? When Will CHZ Get Its Zing Back? On a green candlestick, the current price of CHZ is $0.1677. An oversold Relative Strength Index (RSI) value may help to clarify the recent increase in the token&#8217;s price. However, the market is currently embroiled in a battle between bulls and bears, with prices remaining within the $0.3085-$0.1451 range that prevailed prior to the FTX brouhaha. The market remains slightly mired in the distribution phase, with support and resistance being momentarily breached and reclaimed. This has been true since the month of August. The situation may be deteriorating as CryptoQuant observes an increase in exchange reserves for the coin. According to Messari, the volatility of the asset has been 2.13, indicating that it has been quite shaky. Having settled at -1.23, the returns relative to this volatility likewise exhibit extremely bearish characteristics. Will There Be A Reversal? Nonetheless, the MACD indicator indicates that a reversal is imminent. This may suggest a reversal due to the RSI being oversold. However, because exchange reserves are so high, any positive reversal would be met with a tremendous negative force. A certain bearish breach of the $0.1451 support could cause the current market structure of distribution to collapse. A breach of this support might send the price to the 78.60 Fibonacci level. A breakdown below this level could send the price to $0.0791. As the market recovers from the correction triggered by the FTX crash, CHZ should be able to ride this wave and emerge in a better shape. Related Reading: Bitcoin Price Soars 5% In Last 7 Days – More Increases Coming This Week? CHZ total market cap at $1.02 billion on the daily chart &#124; Featured image: DailyCoin, Chart: TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since the beginning of the 2022 2FIFA World Cup, the value of Chiliz native token has plummeted.</p>
<p>Due to the discovery of various <a href="https://www.jhunewsletter.com/article/2022/12/analyzing-the-controversy-surrounding-the-2022-fifa-world-cup" target="_blank" rel="noopener">issues</a>, the sporting event has been met with some controversies. Not to mention that just a week before the <a href="https://www.fifa.com/fifaplus/en/articles/match-schedule-en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">World Cup’s start,</a> the collapse of the infamous FTX exchange shook the crypto world. But then, this is not the main point here.</p>
<p>Despite some promising advances off-chain, Chiliz continues to struggle. The <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/chiliz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">token</a> is down more than 30% in the last two weeks.</p>
<p>There is a lot of bearish evidence in the technicals and stats. If the price drops below $0.1451, short selling becomes an option.</p>
<p>This added strain to the already overburdened Chiliz ecosystem, which has had trouble drawing in investors and sports fans despite the testnet release of its Chiliz 2.0 <a href="https://www.jhunewsletter.com/article/2022/12/analyzing-the-controversy-surrounding-the-2022-fifa-world-cup">update</a>. However, CoinGecko reported a 1.3% price <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/chiliz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">increase</a> just lately.</p>
<h2>When Will CHZ Get Its Zing Back?</h2>
<p>On a green candlestick, the current price of CHZ is $0.1677. An oversold Relative Strength Index (RSI) value may help to clarify the recent increase in the token&#8217;s price.</p>
<p>However, the market is currently embroiled in a battle between bulls and bears, with prices remaining within the $0.3085-$0.1451 range that prevailed prior to the FTX brouhaha.</p>
<p>The market remains slightly mired in the distribution phase, with support and resistance being momentarily breached and reclaimed.</p>
<p>This has been true since the month of August. The situation may be deteriorating as CryptoQuant <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/chz/summary">observes</a> an increase in exchange reserves for the coin.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://messari.io/asset/chiliz/chart/daily-vol" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Messari,</a> the volatility of the asset has been 2.13, indicating that it has been quite shaky. Having settled at -1.23, the returns relative to this volatility likewise exhibit extremely bearish characteristics.</p>
<h2>Will There Be A Reversal?</h2>
<p>Nonetheless, the MACD indicator indicates that a reversal is imminent. This may suggest a reversal due to the RSI being oversold. However, because exchange reserves are so high, any positive reversal would be met with a tremendous negative force.</p>
<p>A certain bearish breach of the $0.1451 support could cause the current market structure of distribution to collapse. A breach of this support might send the price to the 78.60 Fibonacci level.</p>
<p>A breakdown below this level could send the price to $0.0791. As the market recovers from the correction triggered by the FTX <a href="https://www.themanual.com/culture/what-happened-to-ftx/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">crash</a>, CHZ should be able to ride this wave and emerge in a better shape.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/xZLcrh2c/" width="2047" height="979" /></p>
CHZ total market cap at $1.02 billion on the daily chart | Featured image: DailyCoin, Chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/ajrdy9Lf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView.com</a>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Chiliz-460x274.png" width="460" height="274" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Metaverse Token Axie Infinity (AXS) Suddenly Pumps 25% &#8211; What&#8217;s Happening?</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/axs/metaverse-token-axie-infinity-axs-suddenly-pumps-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AXS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaverse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511153</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[AXS, the native token of Axie Infinity, has seen its price jump in recent hours. The project is a blockchain-based game metaverse in which players collect and breed digital pets called Axies that they can be used in a turn-based card game. At one point, AXS rose to $8.82 after trading as low as $6.41 yesterday and has seen a 28% rally in recent hours. At press time, AXS was at $8.14, still recording a price pump of about 20% over the last 24 hours. Over the last seven days, it&#8217;s up 25%. Today&#8217;s gain is accompanied by a massive surge in trading volume, which has grown to $295 million over the past 24 hours, up 750% from the day before. Currently, Axie Infinity (AXS) has risen to the 52nd largest cryptocurrency with a market cap of nearly $812 million. Related Reading: Elon Musk Lifts Twitter Ban On Dogecoin Accounts; DOGE Pumps 7% – Here’s What Happened However, despite the massive pump, AXS is still one of the biggest losers of the bear market. AXS&#8217; all-time high stand at $164.90 and was reached in November 2021. This represents a whopping 95% loss in value. A look at the 1-day chart reveals that Axie Infinity has still not been able to break out of its downtrend channel. For this, a break above $9.00 would be required. If it fails, AXS would continue to move in bearish territory despite the recent pump. Fundamentals Of Axie Infinity Look Weak Meanwhile, the fundamentals for Axie Infinity continue to look less than rosy. According to the data platform CryptoSlam, the sales volume of Axie Infinity has shrunk massively since the peak on November 3, 2021 at $40.8 million. Since May, volume has been bobbing around below $500,000, though it was still close to $100,000 at the end of October. Yesterday, December 4, it was only $19,500. On Its Way To Decentralization So what is driving the AXS pump? One reason could be the impending decentralization of the project. The team published a blog post today. In it, they shared that a group of over 700 invested and influential community members have come together to shape the future of Axie Infinity. The Lunacian: Axie Contributor Initiative Kickoff! https://t.co/Yjs9njT5Rv &#8212; Axie Infinity &#124; #AxieOrigins (@AxieInfinity) December 5, 2022 The team said it wants to actively work toward an end state. In this state, &#8220;invested&#8221; community members are responsible for making decisions about resourcing the Axie Infinity ecosystem. Currently, the project is still in the initial decentralization phase. However, important progress has been made recently as part of a step-by-step strategy, the blog post states. As progress is made on the decentralization continuum, actions like council formation, resource allocation, on-chain voting, and treasury activation will be unlocked. The ultimate goal is to give the collective the responsibility to advance self-organization. To this end, a collective of established community members of Axie Infinity, the &#8220;town builders,&#8221; was formed back in May. Related Reading: Bitcoin Price Soars 5% In Last 7 Days – More Increase Coming This Week? In July, they decided to bring in a number of contributor electors to play a critical role in an initial pilot program for contributors. In August, the town builders and contributor electors distributed applications for the contributors program. Each proposal submitted hundreds of applications. After being elected town builders by the founding town builder team, the first 700 community members were selected today to participate in the first pilot &#8220;season&#8221; of Axie Contributors. They will contribute to a newly created governance area on Axie Infinity&#8217;s Discord.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AXS, the native token of Axie Infinity, has seen its price jump in recent hours. The project is a blockchain-based game metaverse in which players collect and breed digital pets called Axies that they can be used in a turn-based card game.</p>
<p>At one point, AXS rose to $8.82 after trading as low as $6.41 yesterday and has seen a 28% rally in recent hours. At press time, AXS was at $8.14, still recording a price pump of about 20% over the last 24 hours.</p>
<p>Over the last seven days, it&#8217;s up 25%. Today&#8217;s gain is accompanied by a <a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/elon-musk-lifts-twitter-ban-on-doge-accounts-doge-price-7/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">massive surge </a>in trading volume, which has grown to $295 million over the past 24 hours, up 750% from the day before.</p>
<p>Currently, Axie Infinity (AXS) has <a href="https://newsbtc.com/altcoin/185-million-worth-of-axs-tokens-set-to-be-unlocked-time-to-get-out-of-axie-infinity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">risen</a> to the 52nd largest cryptocurrency with a market cap of nearly $812 million.</p>
<p>However, despite the massive pump, AXS is still one of the biggest losers of the bear market. AXS&#8217; all-time high stand at $164.90 and was reached in November 2021. This represents a whopping 95% loss in value.</p>
<p>A look at the 1-day chart reveals that Axie Infinity has still not been able to break out of its downtrend channel. For this, a break above $9.00 would be required. If it fails, AXS would continue to move in bearish territory despite the recent pump.</p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511162 size-full" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44.png" alt="Axie Infinity AXS USD 2022-12-05" width="2963" height="1672" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44.png 2963w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-460x260.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-860x485.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-768x433.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-1536x867.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-2048x1156.png 2048w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-750x423.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/AXSUSD_2022-12-05_12-57-44-1140x643.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 2963px) 100vw, 2963px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511162" class="wp-caption-text">AXS price still caught in a downtrend channel, 1-day chart Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/uD28avrX/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></figcaption>
<h2>Fundamentals Of Axie Infinity Look Weak</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, the fundamentals for Axie Infinity continue to look less than rosy. According to the data platform CryptoSlam, the sales volume of Axie Infinity has shrunk massively since the peak on November 3, 2021 at $40.8 million.</p>
<p>Since May, volume has been bobbing around below $500,000, though it was still close to $100,000 at the end of October. Yesterday, December 4, it was only $19,500.</p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511163 size-full" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity.png" alt="Axie Infinity Cryptoslam" width="3742" height="1284" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity.png 3742w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-460x158.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-860x295.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-768x264.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-1536x527.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-2048x703.png 2048w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-750x257.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Axie-Infinity-1140x391.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 3742px) 100vw, 3742px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511163" class="wp-caption-text">Axie Infinity sales volume data. Source: <a href="https://www.cryptoslam.io/axie-infinity/sales/summary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cryptoslam</a></figcaption>
<h2>On Its Way To Decentralization</h2>
<p>So what is driving the AXS pump? One reason could be the impending decentralization of the project.</p>
<p>The team published a blog post today. In it, they shared that a group of over 700 invested and influential community members have come together to shape the future of Axie Infinity.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Lunacian: Axie Contributor Initiative Kickoff! <a href="https://t.co/Yjs9njT5Rv">https://t.co/Yjs9njT5Rv</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Axie Infinity | #AxieOrigins (@AxieInfinity) <a href="https://twitter.com/AxieInfinity/status/1599599854602407936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>The team said it wants to actively work toward an end state. In this state, &#8220;invested&#8221; community members are responsible for making decisions about resourcing the Axie Infinity ecosystem.</p>
<p>Currently, the project is still in the initial decentralization phase. However, important progress has been made recently as part of a step-by-step strategy, the blog post states.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>As progress is made on the decentralization continuum, actions like council formation, resource allocation, on-chain voting, and treasury activation will be unlocked.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The ultimate goal is to give the collective the responsibility to advance self-organization. To this end, a collective of established community members of Axie Infinity, the &#8220;town builders,&#8221; was formed back in May.</p>
<p>In July, they decided to bring in a number of contributor electors to play a critical role in an initial pilot program for contributors.</p>
<p>In August, the town builders and contributor electors distributed applications for the contributors program. Each proposal submitted hundreds of applications.</p>
<p>After being elected town builders by the founding town builder team, the first 700 community members were selected today to participate in the first pilot &#8220;season&#8221; of Axie Contributors.</p>
<p>They will contribute to a newly created governance area on Axie Infinity&#8217;s Discord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/AXIE-460x246.jpeg" width="460" height="246" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Price Soars 5% In Last 7 Days &#8211; More Increases Coming This Week?</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin-price-up-5-in-last-7-days/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 10:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bear market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto winter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511127</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[In recent days, Bitcoin has shown a good degree of bullishness. CoinGecko reports that Bitcoin&#8217;s price has increased on a daily and biweekly basis, suggesting that the market may be recovering from FTX&#8217;s fall. Investors at large were also optimistic. The BTC bottom is still in effect, presenting excellent chances for long-term investment. There was little gains with hash ribbon despite the occurrence of a golden cross (chart below), as the price remained unchanged. Also, there is a 50/50 chance of a decline in the market to at least $16.950. Dan Lim, an analyst at CryptoQuant, has made some recent comments that could signal the beginning of a bull market. First, he pointed out that Bitcoin&#8217;s MVRV value is extremely low, almost identical to previous market bottoms. Next, the price of hash has not increased since the golden cross was supposed to be achieved, hence the hash ribbon has failed. Is BTC&#8217;s price about to stage a comeback? If not, is there more suffering in store? Related Reading: ‘Digital Garbage?’ EU Throws $400,000-Metaverse Party That Only Attracted 6 People Bitcoin Price: Inconsistent Numbers The price of bitcoin (BTC) is now displaying highly inconsistent trends. As the RSI rises on the daily time frame, it appears to keep its strong bearish momentum. The expanding Bollinger band supports the bullish outlook for the future. But the current BTC price candle, which is presently trading at $17,315.01, has met a resistance that has not been breached since the price fall on November 11. In addition, a rising triangle pattern contributes to a fairly restricted trading range. Chart: TradingView The token&#8217;s RSI is overbought, indicating that bearishness persists on shorter durations. Although the EMA ribbon appears to be sustaining an upward trend, a bearish crossover could occur within the next few hours or days. As a potential trend reversal looms, BTC investors and traders should closely monitor the present market scenario. Following the recent price fluctuations, the MFI indicates a likely upcoming decline. If the bearish reversal occurs, a decline to $16,970 is conceivable. Strong bearish momentum can drive the price closer to $16,660 or higher. Mixed Opinions About Bitcoin Bitcoin clearly has bullish characteristics. Bitcoin price has been up about 5% in the last week, and some analysts expect it will tally more increases in the coming days. However, as miners and merchants continue to incur losses and reserve levels remain high, Bitcoin&#8217;s path remains challenged. The next consumper price index (CPI) numbers that will be revealed on December 13 will determine whether or not macroeconomics will boost the price of Bitcoin. Related Reading: Crypto Exchange Bybit To Slash 30% Of Its Headcount Due To Crypto Winter Frostbites BTC total market cap at $332 billion on the daily chart &#124; Featured image: Unsplash, Chart: TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In recent days, Bitcoin has shown a good degree of bullishness. CoinGecko <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Bitcoin&#8217;s price has increased on a daily and biweekly basis, suggesting that the market may be recovering from FTX&#8217;s <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kenrapoza/2022/12/04/the-ftx-crisis-brought-investors-to-decentralized-exchanges-heres-why-they-might-leave/?sh=242a4cae9ebc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fall</a>. Investors at large were also optimistic.</p>
<p>The BTC bottom is still in effect, presenting excellent chances for long-term investment. There was little gains with hash ribbon despite the occurrence of a golden cross (chart below), as the price remained unchanged. Also, there is a 50/50 chance of a decline in the market to at least $16.950.</p>
<p>Dan Lim, an analyst at <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/profile/u/DanLim?tab=dashboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CryptoQuant</a>, has made some recent comments that could signal the beginning of a bull market. First, he pointed out that Bitcoin&#8217;s MVRV <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/quicktake/638c053ba60e9b7fa21db775-BTC-MVRV-stays-under-10-more-than-170days" target="_blank" rel="noopener">value</a> is extremely low, almost identical to previous market bottoms.</p>
<p>Next, the price of hash has not increased since the golden cross was supposed to be achieved, hence the hash ribbon has failed. Is BTC&#8217;s price about to stage a comeback? If not, is there more suffering in store?</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Price: Inconsistent Numbers</h2>
<p>The price of bitcoin (BTC) is now displaying highly inconsistent trends. As the RSI rises on the daily time frame, it appears to keep its strong bearish momentum.</p>
<p>The expanding Bollinger band supports the bullish outlook for the future. But the current BTC price candle, which is presently trading at $17,315.01, has met a resistance that has not been breached since the price fall on November 11. In addition, a rising triangle pattern contributes to a fairly restricted trading range.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-511147 aligncenter" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/C1-6-460x298.png" alt="" width="460" height="298" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/C1-6-460x298.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/C1-6.png 681w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" /></p>
Chart: TradingView
<p>The token&#8217;s RSI is overbought, indicating that bearishness persists on shorter durations. Although the EMA ribbon appears to be sustaining an upward trend, a bearish crossover could occur within the next few hours or days.</p>
<p>As a potential trend reversal looms, BTC investors and traders should closely monitor the present market scenario. Following the recent price fluctuations, the MFI indicates a likely upcoming decline.</p>
<p>If the bearish reversal occurs, a decline to $16,970 is conceivable. Strong bearish momentum can drive the price closer to $16,660 or higher.</p>
<h2>Mixed Opinions About Bitcoin</h2>
<p>Bitcoin clearly has bullish characteristics. Bitcoin price has been up about 5% in the last week, and some analysts expect it will tally more increases in the coming days.</p>
<p>However, as miners and merchants continue to incur losses and reserve levels remain high, Bitcoin&#8217;s path remains challenged.</p>
<p>The next consumper price index (CPI) numbers that will be revealed on December 13 will determine whether or not macroeconomics will boost the price of Bitcoin.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/FzULSH74/" width="2047" height="979" /></p>
BTC total market cap at $332 billion on the daily chart | Featured image: Unsplash, Chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/ajrdy9Lf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView.com</a>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/traxer-w3taNRpCl9M-unsplash-460x306.jpg" width="460" height="306" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk Lifts Twitter Ban On Dogecoin Accounts; DOGE Pumps 7% &#8211; Here&#8217;s What Happened</title>
		<link>https://newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/elon-musk-lifts-twitter-ban-on-doge-accounts-doge-price-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 09:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsbtc.com/?p=511124</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[Amidst all of the hustle and bustle surrounding the reorganization of Twitter and the revelations of the &#8220;Twitter Files,&#8221; Elon Musk took the time a few hours ago to fix a pressing problem for the Dogecoin community. In recent days, Musk had declared war on the spam bots on Twitter. In doing so, the algorithm and the Twitter team may have been a bit too harsh. Musk Stands By For The DOGE Community Dogecoin founder Billy Markus wrote on Twitter that more than a dozen Dogecoin Twitter accounts were suspended last weekend, even though they were mainly just tweeting DOGE memes. Markus wrote that these accounts were unjustly suspended: A whole bunch of accounts of people who, as far as I know, generally don&#8217;t do anything but tweet memes and positivity are being suspended. Pretty weird man. Twitter CEO Elon Musk, who through a representative is part of the Dogecoin Foundation&#8217;s five-member advisory team alongside Markus and Vitalik Buterin, responded to the tweet within three hours. Related Reading: Dogecoin Rises: Over 60% Of Holders Continue To Profit Despite FTX Nightmare Musk wrote that his Twitter team had been a bit too aggressive with the suspension of spam bot accounts. &#8220;Team was a bit too intense with spam/bot suspensions. Moving to chill mode,&#8221; Musk replied. Dogecoin founder Markus then confirmed that the accounts have been reactivated &#8220;Welcome back Doge accounts. ty @elonmusk,&#8221; Markus added. welcome back doge accounts ty @elonmusk &#8212; Shibetoshi Nakamoto (@BillyM2k) December 5, 2022 Remarkably, this wasn&#8217;t the only incident where Elon Musk showed his love for Dogecoin over the last weekend. According to Matt Wallace, Elon Musk was spotted on Saturday wearing a black Dogecoin t-shirt, displaying the mascot of DOGE, a Shiba Inu wearing a cowboy hat and sunglasses. Elon Musk just Spotted Wearing a #Dogecoin T-Shirt 🚀❤️😊 pic.twitter.com/MOpphdPdw2 &#8212; Matt Wallace (@MattWallace888) December 3, 2022 Dogecoin Price Pumps 7% After Musk&#8217;s Endorsements The Dogecoin (DOGE) price initially showed no reaction to Elon Musk&#8217;s tweet. This is unusual, as Musk usually triggers a small or large rally with every tweet about the meme coin. However, nothing happened in the first hour after the tweet. This has changed in the last couple of hours. The DOGE price rose to $0.1118 at one point, recording an increase of around 7.5% within an hour. Related Reading: Dogecoin Jumps 10% As Gokhshtein Claims Buterin And Musk Will Work Together For DOGE However, the FOMO quickly flattened out. DOGE was trading at $0.1076 at press time, still posting a gain of around 4% over the past 24 hours. The move has bounced off the important $0.11 resistance zone again. For DOGE it is already the fourth rejection within the last month at this mark. The price had fallen below it on November 7. To initialize a stronger upward movement towards the zone between $0.135 and $0.14, DOGE needs to overcome the key resistance at $0,11 in the 4-hour chart.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amidst all of the hustle and bustle surrounding the reorganization of Twitter and the revelations of the &#8220;Twitter Files,&#8221; Elon Musk took the time a few hours ago to fix a pressing problem for the Dogecoin community.</p>
<p>In recent days, Musk had declared war on the spam bots on Twitter. In doing so, the algorithm and the Twitter team may have been a bit too harsh.</p>
<h2>Musk Stands By For The DOGE Community</h2>
<p>Dogecoin founder Billy Markus <a href="https://twitter.com/BillyM2k/status/1599590476751208449" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> on Twitter that more than a dozen Dogecoin Twitter accounts were suspended last weekend, even though they were mainly just tweeting DOGE memes. Markus wrote that these accounts were unjustly suspended:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>A whole bunch of accounts of people who, as far as I know, generally don&#8217;t do anything but tweet memes and positivity are being suspended. Pretty weird man.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Twitter CEO Elon Musk, who through a <a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-jumps-10-will-buterin-and-musk-work-together/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">representative</a> is part of the Dogecoin Foundation&#8217;s five-member advisory team alongside Markus and Vitalik Buterin, responded to the tweet within three hours.</p>
<p>Musk wrote that his Twitter team had been a bit too aggressive with the suspension of spam bot accounts. &#8220;Team was a bit too intense with spam/bot suspensions. Moving to chill mode,&#8221; Musk replied.</p>
<p>Dogecoin founder Markus then confirmed that the accounts have been reactivated &#8220;Welcome back Doge accounts. ty @elonmusk,&#8221; Markus added.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">welcome back doge accounts </p>
<p>ty <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Shibetoshi Nakamoto (@BillyM2k) <a href="https://twitter.com/BillyM2k/status/1599636941028618240?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Remarkably, this wasn&#8217;t the only incident where Elon Musk showed his love for Dogecoin over the last weekend. According to Matt Wallace, Elon Musk was spotted on Saturday wearing a black Dogecoin t-shirt, displaying the mascot of DOGE, a Shiba Inu wearing a cowboy hat and sunglasses.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Elon Musk just Spotted Wearing a <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Dogecoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Dogecoin</a> T-Shirt <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f680.png" alt="🚀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2764.png" alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f60a.png" alt="😊" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/MOpphdPdw2">pic.twitter.com/MOpphdPdw2</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Matt Wallace (@MattWallace888) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattWallace888/status/1598877422589726720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h2>Dogecoin Price Pumps 7% After Musk&#8217;s Endorsements</h2>
<p>The Dogecoin (DOGE) price initially showed no reaction to Elon Musk&#8217;s tweet. This is unusual, as Musk usually triggers a small or large rally with every <a href="https://newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-on-fire-rallies-after-elon-musk-twitter-deal-confirmation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tweet</a> about the meme coin. However, nothing happened in the first hour after the tweet.</p>
<p>This has changed in the last couple of hours. The DOGE price rose to $0.1118 at one point, recording an increase of around 7.5% within an hour.</p>
<p>However, the FOMO quickly flattened out. DOGE was trading at $0.1076 at press time, still posting a gain of around 4% over the past 24 hours.</p>
<p>The move has bounced off the important $0.11 resistance zone again. For DOGE it is already the fourth rejection within the last month at this mark. The price had fallen below it on November 7.</p>
<p>To initialize a stronger upward movement towards the zone between $0.135 and $0.14, DOGE needs to overcome the key resistance at $0,11 in the 4-hour chart.</p>
<img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-511130 size-full" src="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32.png" alt="Dogecoin DOGE USD 2022-12-05" width="2956" height="1603" srcset="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32.png 2956w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-460x249.png 460w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-860x466.png 860w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-768x416.png 768w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-1536x833.png 1536w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-2048x1111.png 2048w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-750x407.png 750w, https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/DOGEUSD_2022-12-05_10-14-32-1140x618.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 2956px) 100vw, 2956px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-511130" class="wp-caption-text">Dogecoin price rejected at $0,11, 4-hour chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/uD28avrX/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></figcaption>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Dogecoin-2-460x242.png" width="460" height="242" />	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 195/203 objects using apc
Page Caching using disk: enhanced{w3tc_pagecache_reject_reason}
Database Caching 43/49 queries in 0.011 seconds using memcached

Served from: newsbtc.com @ 2022-12-05 23:10:43 by W3 Total Cache
-->